我不打算帮你，你可以走路上班
My office is withdrawn. You can walk to work.
明白了，你极度愤怒
Got it, you're morally outraged.
我们一起把这部分了结了行吗?
Now, can we get through this part?
因为下一部分才真正令人生畏呢
'Cause the next part's awesome.
你怎么能把这样的事合理化呢?
How do you rationalize something like this?
你闯进了史黛西心理心理医生的办公室
You broke into Stacy's therapist's office.
借了把钥匙
Borrowed a key.
还偷了她的治疗记录
And stole her treatment notes.
不，我复印了
Nope, I made copies.
马克是，我引述
Mark is, and I quote
性格孤僻，被动而有侵犯性,拒绝交流
"withdrawn, passive/aggressive, won't communicate.
就象他恨我能走路那样怨恨我
Like he resents me because I can walk."
我不想听这些
I don't wanna hear this.
"盘子在水槽里，如厕掀起厕板
"Dishes in the sink, toilet seat up.
同时，她无法抑制地想……
Meanwhile, she can't stop thinking about..."
我不能读这段
I can't read that.
她是否被匹灰马所迷惑?
Is she obsessed with a gray horse?
还是我？
Or me?
这里说她认为你是一个令人气恼的混蛋
It says she thinks you're an annoying jerk.
那是爱称
It's a pet name.
惊人的部分在这里
Here's the kicker.
他们没有性生活?
They're not having sex?
医生清除了他，但没有发射
Doctor cleared him, but no lift off.
她有挫败感，所以她折磨我
She's frustrated, so she's doc-blocking me.
文字工作，研讨会,搅和我的病人
Paperwork, seminars, meddling with my patients.
现在你有了你需要的证据
And now you've got the proof you need.
干脆把这些私人的心理治疗记录,拿给卡迪
Just take those personal psyche records to Cuddy.
证明史黛西失控了
That'll show her Stacy is out of control.
你不理我吗?
You ignoring me?
我在找我的报纸
While looking for my newspaper.
有效吧?
Efficient, huh?
这里
Over here.
韦医生，来见见我的高人
Dr. Wilson, I want you to meet my stalker.
你的休息室差劲透了
Your waiting room sucks.
我可没给你做治疗
I am not treating you.
因为储藏室事件吗?
Because you're a closet case?
我们，不是一对
We're not, uh, together.
他十分自毁
He is so self-loathing.
我们得走了，那就下班后见吧
Well, we've gotta go now. So maybe see you after work.
不，不
No, no, no.
没人能搞清楚我的问题
Nobody can figure out what's wrong with me.
你衬衫的领子懈了
Well, your shirt is gaping at the collar.
意思是你体重减了
Means you've lost weight.
你脸红，所以发烧,而且呼吸急促
You're flushed, that's fever. And you're short of breath.
同时你的脸上终于有了损伤痕迹
And finally, there's the KS lesion on your face.
意思是你HIV阳性,进一步证明你是艾滋病晚期
Means you're HIV positive, progressed to full-blown aids.
所以，你病了，免疫系统问题
So, you're sick because your immune system
而且还有人朝你打喷嚏
is shot and some one sneezed on you.
这下我可以走了吗？
Can I be excused now?
出色，但是我的免疫系统没问题
Brilliant, but my immune system is fine.
你的集中营体格乞求不同
Your concentration camp physique begs to differ.
拿你的T细胞读数再检查
Get your t-cell count rechecked.
我已经那么做了
I've already done that.
他们做过淋巴瘤T细胞检查吗？
They test for t-celllymphoma?
是阴性的
It was negative.
这些症状会非常吸引艾滋病专家的
All of this would be fascinating to an HIV specialist.
现在在我手杖变成你新男友之前,把我的手杖放开
Now let go of my cane before,it becomes your new boyfriend.
甜心，如果你肯看我的病例,我可以跟它结婚
Honey, I will marry it if you will look at my file.
议会不允许，所以...
Congress says you can't, so...
我都没碰他
I didn't touch him.
他发过敏性休克了
He's going into anaphylactic shock.
去见史黛西
Go see Stacy.
我们给了他epi, 他没事
We gave him an epi, he's fine.
你需要律师，去见史黛西
You need a lawyer, go see Stacy.
你打了个病人
You hit a patient.
四个字，两个错
Four words, two mistakes.
他不是病人，我也没打他
He's not a patient, and I didn't hit him.
你当然没打，去见史黛西
Of course you didn't. Go see Stacy.
我不导致过敏性反应
I didn't cause the anaphylaxis.
没准是他HIV治疗的副作用……
It's probably one of his HIV meds--avacavir...
我预料到了
I'll pass that along.
确保急诊室能一并解决,去见史黛西
Make sure the ER takes him off it. Go see Stacy.
你得给他做治疗
You have to treat him.
医学上讲，这个案例简直小儿科
Medically, this case is a snooze fest.
艾滋病加感染
Aids plus infection.
你不管他，他就以袭击控告你
You don't treat him, he charges you with assault.
我不会因为他说我攻击他,就得按事实处置
Just 'cause he says I hit him, doesn't make it true.
看啊，我被裸体拉拉队员包围……
Watch. I am surrounded by naked cheer leaders.
看见了?
See?
尽管我今早喜欢来点体力活
Although I like my chances of some action this morning.
我忘了周三是妓女日,这个可以等等再说
I forgot Wednesday was hooker day.,This could have waited.
你迫使我到你家跟你见面
You make me meet you at your house.
你丈夫很方便的不在家
Your husband is conveniently absent.
马克在做理疗
Mark's at physio.
我在等杀虫的人来走不了
I'm stuck waiting for the exterminator.
我昨晚看见一只老鼠
I saw a rat last night.
我很惊讶你的脚还踩着地
Well, I'm surprised your feet are touching the floor.
我都睡不着觉
I barely slept.
马克干嘛来着?
What was Mark up to?
记忆里，最快爬上格里高山峰
Memory serves, a quick climb up Mt. Gregory
而你在打海豹的时候睡着了
and you'd doze through a seal hunt.
抛锚，尖叫
Clubbing, shrieking.
你干嘛呢?
What are you doing?
对不起，这简直把我逼疯了
Sorry, it was driving me nuts.
你痛恨洗碗
You hate washing dishes.
人可以变
People change.
我能确保你今夜熟睡如婴儿
I could make sure you sleep like a baby tonight.
我宁愿自己对付
I'd rather take care of it myself.
我是在跟老鼠谈条件
I was referring to the rat.
特伦顿灭害所派的是个同性恋
Trenton pest is sending a guy.
干嘛呢?
What's going on?
不象你想的那样
It's not what you think.
我知道看上去我们象在洗碗
I know it looks like we're cleaning dishes
但其实我们在做爱呢
but actually, we're having sex.
我们在工作
We're working.
哇，真希望我能成为个医生
Wow, wish I'd become a doctor.
毫无污点的活着
Place'd be spotless.
拿出10分钟来，把那家伙治好,别再搅和了
Take ten minutes, cure the guy, and stop whining.
我给你凯莱
I give you Kalvin Ryan.
私下里精彩，报纸上无聊
So flamboyant in person, so boring on paper.
明显的机会性感染，TB 或 PCP.
Obviously got an opportunistic infection, probably TB or PCP.
你看他的病例了吗？
Have you read his file?
开始了，但我发现了双重人格
I started, but I found the characters two-dimensional.
他上周去了一间艾滋病诊所
He went to an HIV clinic last week.
TB, PCP, MAC, CMV, HSV测试全是阴性
Tested negative for TB, PCP, MAC, CMV, HSV.
不是感染
It's not an infection.
艾滋病诊所，病人很少，钱很多,重做测试
HIV clinic, so few patients, so much money. Redo the tests.
结果是有道理的
The results make sense.
凯的t细胞读数200
Kalvin's t-cells are at 200.
足以抵抗感染
That's strong enough to fight infection.
对，寄生虫
Fine, parasite.
不对，大便测试是阴性
Nope, stool sample was negative.
两个以前他的T细胞减到了30
Two months ago he was down to 30 t-cells.
然后他改变了用药,是免疫系统反弹
Then he changed his meds, is immune system rebounds
他的滤过性病毒承载量减低了
his viral load drops.
一切都变好了，可他的病变重了
Everything's getting better, but he's getting sicker.
面对吧，也许是个有趣的病例
Face it, this might be an interesting case.
如果他的免疫系统过强如何?
What if his immune system is too strong?
HIV是自身免疫系统疾病,不可能的
And autoimmune disease with HIV, that's impossible.
他的HIV新药唤醒了他的系统
His new HIV meds kicked his system out of a sound sleep.
被饥饿、暴躁地唤醒后急需作战
Wakes up hungry, cranky, spoiling for a fight.
当无法找到积极感染时
When it doesn't find an active infection
它开始寻找过去感染的无害痕迹进行进攻
it starts attacking the harmless remnants of old infections.
免疫边缘系统综合症
Immune reconstitution syndrome.
他的药使他强壮后他把自己弄病了
His meds made him so much better, he made himself sick.
听上去……
Sounds pretty--
真无聊
boring!
一点趣味都没有
This is so not interesting.
胸部X透视找到陈旧感染,注射类固醇吧
Chest x-ray to find the old infections. Start him on steroids.
如果你错了，类固醇会击败他的免疫系统
If you're wrong, steroids will tank his immune system.
他的情况会变坏
He'll get worse.
那样就有趣了
Now that would be interesting.
Coumadin在哪?
Where's the coumadin?
如果你的病人有血液问题
If your patient's got a blood problem
血液稀释剂就会...
then blood thinner's aren't exactly...
是给史黛西的老鼠预备的
it's for Stacey's rat.
死于抗凝血剂
Death by anticoagulation.
想籍杀死动物赢回史黛西？
Trying to win Stacy back by killing an animal.
非常洞穴人
Very caveman.
我才不要她回来呢
I don't want her back.
我只是想让她承认对我的感觉而已
I just want her to admit her feelings for me.
我去找卡迪
I go to Cuddy.
卡迪炒掉她或重新分配她
Cuddy fires her or reassigns her.
任何结果我都高兴
Either way, I'm happy.
如果你想赢回她，要么就告诉她...
If you want her back, either tell her...
或者干脆，闭嘴...
or better yet, shut up...
痛哭着象其他人一样入睡
and cry yourself to sleep like everybody else.
你好，我是万马克，春街1724号
Hi, this is Mark Warner. 1724 Spring street.
不用派人来了
Uh, listen, you don't need to send that guy down.
我们抓到老鼠了
We caught him.
不，你把账单送到P_P医院
No, you should send the bill to Princeton Plainsboro hospital.
交韦医生收即可
Attention Dr. James Wilson. Yeah.
你的淋巴结不肿，挺好
Your lymph nodes aren't swollen, that's good.
也许该让蔡大夫检查
Maybe Dr. Chase should check.
对不起，我腾不出手来
Sorry, my hand's full.
他太漂亮了，不可能是异性恋
He's too pretty to be straight.
你做过模特吗?
You ever done any modeling?
真有人为此献身吗?
Does anyone actually fall for that line?
每天
Every day.
你以为我怎么就做了摄影师的?
Why do you think I became a photographer?
我猜你们不会在工作日约会的吧
I'm guessing you guys didn't think about dating on career day.
我热爱我的工作
I love my job.
真的吗?
Really?
你看上去是“异常满足”那类的
You seem more the "find it exceptionally satisfying" type.
我不肯定这有区别
I'm not sure there's a difference.
你妈妈死于糖尿病
Your mom died of diabetes.
你父亲的健康如何？
How's your dad's health?
最后听说的时候，好像是硬化
Last I heard, he had cirrhosis.
爱是爱
Love is love.
满足是社会认可,乐趣都可以延迟
Satisfying is social validation. Fun can wait.
我有乐趣
I have fun.
对，她二月有些计划
Yeah, she's got some scheduled for February.
最后听说你父亲?
Last you heard of your father?
我16岁他就把我赶走了
He threw me out when I was 16.
其实都一样
It's just as well.
我已经厌烦了生日时收到弹子枪作礼物
I got tired of getting BB guns for my birthday
因为我想要芭比娃娃
when I'd asked for a barbie.
父亲们有时很贴心的
Dads can be real sweet hearts.
嗯，敏感可爱
Mmm, sensitive and cute.
他很可爱
He's cute.
它跑进了那边的通风管道
He ran into that heating vent right there.
希望马克的愤怒能最终消失
Hopefully Mark's anger will go away eventually.
他没生气，他只是不喜欢你
He's not angry, he just doesn't like you.
没什么特别的
Nothing unique there.
也没看他对你有多热情
Didn't seem really wild about you either.
他对我没问题
He's fine with me.
他愤怒，在小组是那么说的
He's angry. He said so in group.
他当然愤怒
Of course he's angry.
要面对累月的痛苦的理疗
He's looking at months of painful physio.
他生你的气
He's mad at you.
他不是那么说的
There's no way he said that.
可是事实
No. But it's true.
他恨你能走路
He resents you for being able to walk.
我经历过
I've been there.
我恨了你好长时间
I resented you for a hell of a long time.
过去时态吗?
Past tense?
也许是医院
Might be the hospital.
什么?
What?
时机不好吗？你在哪里？
Bad time? Where are you?
在你女友的家，别在意呻吟和咆哮声吧
at your girlfriend's place.,Ignore the moaning and squeaking.
他的肺部太害怕了
His lungs are too scarred to tell
不告诉我们是哪个,旧感染点带来边缘系统感染
which infection triggered the immune reconstitution.
他抽烟吗?
He a smoker?
对，而且不只是香烟
Yes, and possibly more than cigarettes.
他的总氧化测试显示其为吸毒者
His tox screen came back positive for recreational drugs.
不奇怪，也没有医学关联
Not surprising, not medically relevant.
他的心脏看上去有点大
His heart looks a little enlarged.
是典型的AZT副作用
That's a typical side effect of AZT.
凯最近的感染是什么?
What were Kalvin's most recent infections?
Toxo, CMV, 和PVP
Toxo, CMV, and PVP.
好，我们假设是其中一个
Well, let's assume it's one of those.
服用CMV...
Give me ganciclovir for CMV...
我们都听不见你，你在哪?
We can hardly hear you. Where are you?
在柜子里
In a closet.
你女友的其他男友来了
Your girlfriend's other boyfriend showed up.
服用CMV
Ganciclovir for the CMV.
toxo用磺胺嘧啶
Sulfadiazine for the toxo.
PCP用Bactrim
Bactrim for PCP.
得走了
Gotta go.
杀戮时刻到
It's killin' time.
你的总氧化剂结果阳性...
Your TOX screen came back positive for...
安非他明结晶成瘾
crystal meth and ecstasy.
毒品成瘾十分危险
Recreational drugs are dangerous to begin with.
但对于HIV症...
But for someone with HIV...
我没把他们当维他命服用
I didn't mistake them for vitamins.
我是“PNP”男生
I'm a PNP boy.
“舞会和玩乐”，毒品和性交
Party 'n' play. Drugs and sex.
你不赞成
You don't approve.
性交带避孕套吗?
Does the sex include condoms?
如果是阴性那肯定,如果是阳性...
If he's negative, sure. If he's positive...
已经湿了谁还要穿雨衣啊?
why put on a raincoat if you're already wet?
你可能会得肝炎或其他类型的HIV
You could get hepatitis or another strain of HIV.
我还可能被公车撞死呢
Or I could get hit by a bus.
艾滋病已经不是必死症了
Aids isn't a death sentence anymore.
我不想有遗憾
I don't wanna have any regrets.
你咳多久了?
How long have you been coughing?
一个小时什么的
Uh, about an hour or so.
来个深呼吸
Try to take a deep breath.
怎么了?
What is it?
我想是血
I think it's blood.
我建议快速暴露性预防措施
I recommend post exposure prophylaxis.
感染机会细微
The chances of conversion are slim
但我仍希望对你进行三个疗程的,抗病毒药物治疗
but I'd like to put you on three anti-viral medications.
Nalphenovair, zedovudine,和 lamivudine
Nalphenovair, zedovudine, and lamivudine.
有副作用
There are side-effects.
头疼、恶心、清晰的梦境
Headache, nausea, vivid dreaming.
并在六周、三个月和半年时,做HIV测试
You'll be tested for HIV at six weeks, three months, six months...
很有趣
Very interesting.
他把感染的血咳进,卡麦伦嘴和眼睛里
He coughs infected blood in Cameron's eyes and mouth.
那样有趣？
That's interesting.
咳嗽的部分,不是“进卡麦伦”部分
The coughing part, not the "in Cameron" part.
新症状
New symptom.
他肺部血管破裂
Blood vessel ruptured in his lung.
我缝合了
I closed the tear.
免疫边缘问题被排除了
Well, it takes immune reconstitution off the table.
那么什么显露出来了呢?
What's it put on the table?
没事，她不在这里
It's Okay, she's not here.
你可以省略掉好人举止
You can skip the nice guy acts.
你知道，人类可以有人类的情感
You know, some human beings are actually capable of human feelings.
我是否在意都无法改变历史
My giving a damn or not is not gonna change what happened.
是不是排泄系统综合症
Could be good pasture's syndrome.
没有水肿和血尿
No edema. No bloody urine.
面部损伤可能源于肺部损伤,躯体失血
KS on his face could mean KS in his lungs with bleeding from the lesions.
有的话在肺部缝合时我会看到
I would have seen them when I repaired the tear in his lung.
肉芽肿?
Wegener's granulomatosis?
那会引起类固醇反应
Wegener's would have responded to steroids.
或许你该回家去休息
Maybe you should go home, take the rest of the day.
我没事
I'm fine.
哦，很好
Oh, this is good.
他假意关心，而你假装不在意
He's pretending to care, you're pretending not to.
我觉得我们该重新考虑毒品
I think we should reconsider drugs.
凯用安非他明结晶
Kalvin uses crystal meth.
在他用手杖杵我的时候
Concerned enough about his health to stalk me
就已经足够注意了
while indulging in deadly street drugs.
对矛盾的研究
A study in contradictions.
有趣，但不相关
Interesting, still not medically relevant.
如果他的毒品污染了就相关了
It could be if his drugs were tainted.
他们用电解酸、碱和灯油加工晶体
They cook meth with battery acid, lye, lantern fuel.
找到凯的药片，测试毒素
Find Kalvin's pills, test for toxins.
福满，你跟我走
Foreman, you're with me.
另一个病例我需要协助
I need a consult on another case.
我们有另一个病例吗?
We have another case?
是个屁兜交易
It's a hip-pocket deal.
病人显示明显的颈部倾斜
Patient presents with a distinct neck tilt.
歪脖?是运动员吗？
Wry neck. Is he an athlete?
是正规跑步的
He's a regular runner.
有相关运动疼痛吗?
Any pain associated with movement?
他没抱怨过
None that he's complained of.
最佳的相关问题是耳朵和肺
Best case scenario, an infection in the ear or lungs.
最坏的情况是脑干瘤
Worst case, brain stem tumor.
需要做核磁共振,分层扫描全套检查
Should do an MRI, cat scan, full workup.
我不认为行，没保险
Uh, I don't think so. No insurance.
这没药
No drugs in here.
我查浴室
I'll take the bathroom.
工作后喝一杯如何?
How about a drink after work?
帮你排遣一下
Take your mind off what happened.
卡麦伦?
Cameron?
我也许带HIV，喝酒又不能冲走它
I might have HIV. A drink's not gonna wash it away.
可你也或许没法缩小它啊
There's, like, zero chance of you contracting the virus.
没法和或许没法不一样
Big difference between like zero and zero.
感染控制那家伙说什么了?
What did the infection control guy tell you?
他挺安心的
He was very reassuring.
一个劲告诉我,医院会负担我所有医药费用
Kept reminding me that the hospital covers all my medical costs.
明显忘记提到如果我的测试阳性
Apparently forgot to mention that if I do test positive
他们就诉诸法律
that they'll pass it onto legal.
而一旦诉诸法律他们就会尽力..
And legal will dig up any dirt they can,trying to prove that I'm A...
我是因为有毒瘾或磕药而染上HIV
drug user or a tramp and that's why I have HIV.
他们不会发现什么吧，对吗?
It's not like they're gonna find anything, right?
对
Right.
瞧这个
Check this out.
凯的作品
Kalvin's a photographer.
破碎的鳞茎作为道具
The broken bulbs were props.
玻璃闪着30年代的磷光
The glass is from 1930s fluorescents.
有些鳞茎有日期标签
Some of the bulbs are date-stamped.
二战前，磷光球含大量Be元素
Pre-world war II, fluorescent bulbs,contained large amounts of beryllium.
Be吸进肺部
Beryllium dustinflames the lungs
肺叶硬化，病人无法呼吸
they get rigid, patient can't breathe.
我父亲是急性Be中毒,导致肺部症状报告的合著人
My father co-authored a paper on acute berylliosis.
只一小会儿的功夫,我还真以为你挺聪明呢
For a moment there, I thought you were smart.
卡麦伦，给凯做肺部活检
Cameron, get a biopsy of Kalvin's lung tissue.
做个绘图分析
Run a spectrographic analysis.
我能应付
I can handle it.
没理由使整个团队都冒感染的危险
No reason to risk exposing the entire team.
到时候让我去折磨谁?
Then who would I torment?
我对……发生的事感到抱歉
I'm sorry...about what happened.
最好不要说话
It's best not to talk.
你会感到刺痛
You'll feel a sharp pinch.
这其实是要把你的肺揪一点下来
This actually is gonna grab a piece of your lung.
你们到我酒店里去找什么?
What were you guys looking for at my hotel?
你的毒品
Your drugs.
以为你用了有毒的晶体
Thought maybe you'd used toxic meth.
我们也知道你曾,暴露在放射元素Be的环境中
We'll know if you were exposed to beryllium in a few hours.
如果你们还感兴趣的话
Well, if you're still curious
东西就在我椅子上的包里
it's in my bag over there on the chair.
你把毒品带进了医院?
You brought drugs into the hospital?
真高兴在你酒店浪费时间
Glad I wasted my time at your hotel.
我告诉你我用了
I told you I used.
你又没跟我要样本
You didn't ask me for a sample.
你不是因为这个生气
You're not pissed about this.
你是因为我朝你咳血才生气的
You're mad because I coughed blood on you.
那是事故
That was an accident.
别装好人了，没用的
Won't you stop being nice, it's useless.
而且更糟，郁闷
And worse, it's boring.
生气吧
Get angry.
一个愚不可及的夜生活,就让我患了HIV
I had one stupid night. I end up with HIV.
你能想像我当时有多生气吗?
Do you have any idea how pissed-off I was?
这又不是你的错
This wasn't your fault.
你擅闯我的房子?
You broke into my house?
没辙，马克不在
Well, I had to. Mark isn't here.
他去做理疗了
He has physio.
哦，真的? 他怎样了?
Oh, really? How's he doing?
所有的乳酪怎么了?
What happened with all the cheese?
在麦史迪吃到更多coumadin前,我得把它们都处理了
Well, I had to get rid of it before,Steve Mcqueen ate any coumadin.
我给你的老鼠起了名
I named your rat.
史迪老歪着头
Steve's tilting his head.
任何神经系统医生都会告诉你
Any neurologist will tell you
是脑干瘤的感染结果所致
that suggests an infection or a brain stem tumor.
死了就都治好了
Death cures both those things.
哦，我们不能杀死它
Oh, we can't kill him.
如果是感染
If it's an infection
该是由你房子里其他东西所致
it could be caused by something in your house.
其他可能影响到你们的东西
Something that could affect you guys.
闻闻
Smell this.
味道象尿吗?
Does it smell like urine?
哦
Oh!
你少了芦笋吗?
You missing any asparagus?
好，填上这个
Okay, stuff these.
如果他没变好，那就是瘤
If he doesn't get better, then it's a tumor.
然后干嘛，化疗吗?
Then what, chemo?
麦史迪没毛?
Steve Mcqueen without hair?
他早死都该庆幸
It's a blessing he died young.
喂
Hello.
哦，嗨，甜心
Oh, hi, honey.
对不起跟你错过了，对
I'm sorry I missed you. Yeah.
我到家了
I came home.
好，那一会儿见吧
All right, I'll see you in a few minutes.
再见，甜心
Okay. Bye, hon.
胸疼
Chest hurts.
心律100继续攀升,可能是过敏反应
Heart rate's 100 and climbing. Could bean allergic reaction.
颈部纹理清晰,应当是心包渗出
Neck veins are up. Must be pericardial effusion.
无喘息声
No wheezing.
肺部破裂肯定又开了
The tear in his lungs must have re-opened.
凯，你的心脏附近有出血
Kalvin, you're bleeding into the area around your heart.
我要死了，无法呼吸
I'm dying.I can't breathe.
血液冲击你的心脏
The blood's crushing your heart.
我们解决了，你会好的
Once we remove it, you'll be fine.
如果我死了，请告诉我爸爸...
If I die, please tell my dad...
你不会死
you're not going to die.
告诉他我很抱歉
Tell him sorry.
血在哪里?
Where's the blood?
根本没有啊
It's clear.
只有一个理由导致这样
Only one other thing could cause this.
心脏有瘤
A tumor in his heart.
CT 证实凯心脏有一个大的
CT confirmed a mass in Kalvin's heart
肺部还有些小的
and several smaller ones in his lungs.
所以他的心脏才肥大,而不是抗艾滋病药物导致
That's why his heart's enlarged. Not the AZT.
你没事吧？
You Okay?
她没事，可能是被问题搞烦了
She's fine. Probably getting bored with the question.
心肺的麻烦
Masses in the heart and lungs.
我们见的是哪类的癌症?
What kind of cancer are we looking at?
也许不是癌
They may not be cancerous.
是典型的非霍氏淋巴瘤
This is classic non-hodgkins lymphoma.
HIV 阳性病人长了早期心脏瘤？
HIV positive patient with a primary heart mass?
也许是类肉状瘤
It could be sarcoidosis.
他的肺部活检是阴性
His lung tissue is negative.
淋巴瘤是绝症,类肉状瘤是可治的
Lymphoma's a death sentence, sarcoidosis is treatable.
耳部感染也是
So's an ear infection.
但他两项测试皆非阳性
Since he didn't test positive for that either.
我要给他做siltzbach测试
I wanna do the kveim siltzbach test.
你知道那样,卡迪会让你写多少报告吗？
Do you have any idea how much paperwork Cuddy's gonna need signed?
做吧
Do it.
那...
So...
病人的父亲怎样了?
how is the patient's father?
告诉我父亲很抱歉
"Tell my dad I'm sorry."
也许跟向公牛摇红旗一样效果
Might as well have waved a red flag at a bull.
他并没要来
He's not coming.
嗯，并不是悲剧
Well, it's not a tragedy.
爸爸不想看他，他也不想看爸爸
Dad doesn't wanna see him, he doesn't wanna see the dad.
你是唯一一个想看他们在一起的人
You're the only one who wants them together.
他要求……
He asked--
他以为要死了,人快死时会说谎的
he thought he was dying. Dying people lie too.
会希望少工作，多行善
Wished they'd worked less. They'd been nicer.
为小猫开孤儿院
They'd opened orphanages for kittens.
如果你真想干点什么,那就干吧
If you really wanna do something, you do it.
不为有回应而做
You don't save it for a sound bite.
你要死的时候想怎样来着?
What did you say when you thought you were dying?
换个角度说...
On the other hand...
他父亲把他扔出来
his dad tossed him out.
那么我们的伙计要道什么歉?
So what's our guy want to apologize for?
人人都有遗憾
Everybody has regrets.
如果肺和心有肌肉生长
If the growths in your lungs and heart are sarcoid
那么你的身体会意识到这个材料
your body will recognize this material.
那么我们就会在手臂上看到反应
And we'll see a reaction on your arm.
你真想见你父亲吗?
Did you really want to see your dad?
你打给他了吗?
You called him?
谢谢
Thanks.
要不他就会来把我修理一番
He would've come and tried to straighten me out.
你怎么撑下来?
How are you holding up?
我挺好
I'm fine.
令人信服
Convincing.
你把我的毒品怎么了?
What'd you do with my drugs?
实验室在做完试演后会处置
The lab disposes of them after analysis.
真可惜
Too bad.
它们本可以让你爽它一下
They could have done you some good.
我可不来那套
They're not really my thing.
你知道我希望你没被感染
You know, I hope you don't have it.
但是得了HIV令我获益良多
But getting HIV might have been the best thing that ever happened to me.
我曾是个好孩子
I used to be a good boy.
从不想惹任何人生气
Never wanted to piss anybody off.
按常规办事，讨好别人
Playing by the rules makes everybody else happy.
现在我很快乐
Now I'm happy.
所以每次他做理疗你就出现？
So you just show up every time he's at physio?
当然不是
Of course not.
还有他做心理咨询的时候,外出跟朋友吃饭的时候
Also when he's at group therapy or out for dinner with friends.
而当她告诉马克你顺便...
And when she happens to mention to Mark that you dropped by...
你把一切都告诉你妻子吗?
you tell your wife everything?
那是个步骤
It's a...process.
可史黛西并不需要隐瞒马克这个啊
But Stacy doesn't have any reason to hide this from Mark.
她该知道，马克对你在那没意见
As far as she knows, Mark's okay with you being there.
我打赌她尽量少跟马克提到我
My bet is she mentions me to Mark as little as possible.
她想他觉得她还对我有感情
She thinks that he thinks that she still has feelings for me.
你知道她为什么那么想吗?
And you know why she thinks that?
因为她还对你有感情?
Because she still has feelings for you?
如果你对，她确实告诉他了
If you're right, she did tell him
我今晚就进不了门了
and I don't get through the door tonight.
如果我对...
If I'm right...
我们要在这呆多久?
So how long do we stay here?
直到有事发生为止
Until something happens.
我们在这他才不会出来呢
He's not gonna come out with us right here.
我们在下风口，而且他有听力丧失
We are downwind, and he seems to have a hearing loss.
他不瞎吧
He's not blind.
麦史迪才不会在困难前退却呢
Steve Mcqueen does not run from danger.
抗生素，或者...
Antibiotics, on the other hand...
他在药片周围吃?
he ate around the pill?
聪明
Smart.
承认吧，你喜欢他
Admit it, you like him.
对于老鼠来说，他挺好
He's all right. For a rat.
你想知道他有多酷吗?
You wanna know how cool he is?
他的尿检显示含量中包括氰化物,甲醛和铅
His urine showed traces of,hydrogen cyanide, formaldehyde, lead.
他是烟民
He's a smoker.
是你丈夫抽的
Your husband's been lighting up.
他有够蠢，那样会导致他的aip……
Which is particularly stupid,,given that it could 'cause his aip to--
好了，是我对着排气孔吹的烟,马克不知道
Okay, I blow my smoke into the vent so Mark doesn't know.
我总知道
I always knew.
你在吹牛
You're bluffing.
我手术后的两个星期你开始的
You started two weeks after my surgery.
薄荷的……一个月后是轻型的
Menthols... then lights after a month.
你干嘛不说话啊?
Why didn't you say anything?
因为那帮助我监视你的痛苦指数
'Cause it helped me monitor your misery level.
出去遛一下一天过的不错
One trip outside was a good day.
6根以上，一点糟透了
Upwards of six, you were in hell.
你可以问我我的感觉
You could have asked me how I was.
我已经知道了
I already knew.
我很遗憾你感觉凄惨
I'm sorry you were miserable.
抱歉给你带来这么多痛苦
Sorry I caused you so much pain.
看看你是不是对喝酒改主意了
Thought you'd change your mind about that drink.
进来
Come on in.
你该换衣服了
You should get changed.
校园里有个新地方……
There's this new place on campus that looks--
你high了吧?
Are you high?
我以为实验室处置了毒品
I thought the lab disposed of the drugs.
不是所有的
Not all of it.
哦，慢点……
Uh, slow down.
你们这些学生...
Your pupils are dilated. You're not...
来吧，小蔡,别这会儿把我变成个好人
Come on, Chase, don't turn into a good guy on me now.
你迟了
You're late.
而且疲劳
And hung over.
或者不是
Or maybe not.
你拿个老鼠干嘛?
Why do you have a rat?
嫉妒吗?
Jealous?
滚出我房间
Out of my room!
你竟敢把这安在我身上
Don't you dare put this on me!
我不会哀求你的，爸爸
I'm not gonna grovel, dad.
我不要求那样
That's not what I'm asking for.
就是，你说的你不打电话
Like hell it isn't. You said you didn't call.
别介意我，来看表演的
Don't mind me. Just here for the show.
不会有了
Well, there's not gonna be any.
那个大道歉在哪里?
What happened to the big apology?
昨天他还在那,“哦，爸爸，我很抱歉”
Yesterday, he was all, "daddy, I'm so sowwy."
这没你事
This is none of your business.
你该在杵我之前就想到
You should have thought of that before you stalked me.
现在我的兴趣被提起来了
Now I'm interested.
那么他要道什么歉?
So what's he gotto apologize for?
你是那个把他扔出去的人
You're the one who tossed him out.
哦，我干嘛要那样做?
Now, why would I do that?
我不知道，因为那样,跟打猎的伙伴吹很久带劲
I don't know, 'cause it's tough to brag to your hunting buddies
你儿子是个奇才
that your son knows all the words to the wiz.
撒谎
That's a lie.
42号街
42nd street.
干脆喝酒然后打他更容易
Much easier just to get drunk and beat him.
可以解释他恨你
Explains his hating you.
和你的硬化
Also your cirrhosis.
也可以解释我说的越多你越出汗
Also why the more I talk, the more you sweat.
但不能解释...
What it doesn't explain...
他向你道歉的理由
is why he's gotta apologize to you.
由跟朋友分享特别的玩具,而带来的愧疚吗？
Residual guilt for sharing your special toy with other boys?
算了吧
Just leave it alone.
想在你死后给这个老顽固,留下内行平静吗?
You just wanna leave the bigot with,some peace of mind after you're gone?
这里没什么事,我跟他……
Look, this has got nothing, and I mean nothing
成为同性恋无关
to do with him being gay.
凯说的事是跟他妈妈的事有关
Kal brought this on himself with what he did to his mother.
他偷走了她的长相?
He steal her signature look?
不
No.
不，他杀了她
No, he killed her.
凯说谎了
Kalvin lied.
是啊，真令人惊讶
Yeah, that certainly is shocking.
妈妈的肾脏失效，需要移植
Mom's kidneys were failing, she needed a transplant.
他们测试了凯,他的合适
They tested Kalvin, he was a match.
他也是HIV阳性
He was also positive for HIV.
妈妈没有再找到捐献者，她死了
Mom never found a qualified donor. She dies.
悲惨的故事
Tragic tale.
在稳定时刻的有点激情过度
Undercut slightly by the rapid-fire delivery and constant movement.
今早喝太多咖啡了吗?
Too much coffee this morning?
他又没杀她
He didn't kill her.
我们的身体又不是,给父母捐献的农场
Our bodies aren't donor farms for our parents.
不是80年代
It's not 1980.
我们知道 HIV 可遗传
We know how HIV is transmitted.
如果凯通过未防护性生活得到HIV
If Kalvin got HIV through unprotected sex
爸爸当然有权生气
dad has every right to be pissed.
那你永远都用避孕套吗?
So you always use a condom?
哦，对
Uh, yeah.
底层兄弟不得已而为啊
Brothers on the down-low got to.
还没为后辈准备好,你呢?
Not ready for any foreman juniors yet.
职业女性真难对付
You?
你不选小蔡吗?
You're not gonna poll Chase?
我不是蠢人
I'm not an idiot.
显然不是
Obviously not.
当有机会的时候谁不会睡一个,被毒品迷倒的同事呢？
Who doesn't sleep with a drugged-out colleague when they have a chance?
韦森呢?
Where's Wilson?
我们有检验结果了
We got the results of the kveim test.
那么，我得癌了吗?
So, I have cancer?
是的
In all likelihood, yeah.
非霍氏淋巴瘤
Non-hodgkins lymphoma.
我……快死了吗
And I am...dying.
我们需要做肿瘤活检
We need to biopsy the tumor.
靠近你的大动脉,所以取样十分冒险
It's near your aorta, so getting,that sample carries serious risks.
我爸还在这吗?
Is my dad still here?
他还没进来吗?
He hasn't been in?
我们要在你心脏附近,注入颜色使其在ct上可见
We'll inject the dye around your heart to make the tumor visible on the CT.
然后外科医生输入导向管
Then a surgeon inserts a guidewire
指挥其进入心脏
runs it up into your heart
在那里他取肿瘤的样本
where he takes a small piece of that tumor
然后我们就可以在显微镜下观察了
so we can look at it under the microscope.
Atavan.
Atavan
希望能帮你安静下来
It'll help settle you down.
为什么你这么冷静？
Why are you so calm?
不必晶体的帮助
Not coming off meth helps.
昨晚该不会再发生了吧
Last night probably shouldn't happen again.
你认为我想要吗?
Do you think I want it to?
当俩人性交后，除非不好
When two people have had sex, unless it sucks
如果他们能再做,他们会做的
if they can do it again, they're gonna do it again.
那样事情会变复杂
And that's when things get complicated.
而且不差
And it didn't suck.
那么现在你又有了新理由,可以在你今生挚爱前晃了
So now you've gotta drum up another excuse to be around the love of your life.
在打另一个病人吧
Could hit another patient.
不，不喜欢重复
Nah, don't like to repeat myself.
人们会说我刻板
People will say I'm formulaic.
那样也排除了,放走耗子再去抓的可能性
Well that rules out letting the rat go so you can catch him again.
我不能那样做
I can't do that.
史迪需要做两周的抗生素治疗,和无烟环境
Steve needs two weeks antibiotics and a smoke free environment.
香烟加重了他的感染
Cigarettes aggravated his infection.
那老鼠真有病吗?
The rat is actually sick?
那玩意能污染整个医院
That thing could infect the entire hospital.
史迪的感染不传染人类
Steve's infection is not contagious to humans.
我真蠢，怎么会漏掉coplasmosis?
I'm an idiot. How do I miss my coplasmosis?
那是孩子的父亲吗?
Was that the kid's father?
对
Yeah.
记得黑死病吗？从老鼠开始的
Remember the black death? Started with rats.
他在走廊里干嘛？
Well, what's he doing in the hallway?
那孩子准备好活检了吗?
Is the kid getting his biopsy already?
他不想进屋
He just won't go in the room.
谁知道他还有什么,寄生虫，细菌感染？
Who knows what else he has. Parasites, bacterial infection?
那孩子没有寄生虫
The kid doesn't have parasites.
不是男孩，是老鼠
Not the kid, the rat.
他还在出汗吗?
Was he still sweating?
老鼠是尾部出汗
Rats only sweat through their tails.
不是老鼠，是爸爸
Not the rat, the dad.
他们从哪来?
Where are they from?
蒙坦那，怎么了？
Uh, Montana. What's going on?
你对了，是寄生虫
You were right, it's a parasite.
取消活检，会致命的
Cancel the biopsy, it'll kill him.
嗨，爸爸，跟我来
Hey, daddy, come with me.
对啊，我才不进去
Yeah, uh, I'm not going in there.
你儿子要跟你说话
Your son asked to talk to you.
他干嘛来?
Why is he here?
他要跟你说话
He wanted to talk to you.
你们过去常一起打猎是吧?
Did you two used to hunt together?
狐狸，你们杀狐狸吗?
Foxes. Did you kill foxes?
是蒙坦那
It's Montana.
你们肺里的不是瘤
Those masses in your chest are not tumors.
是一个小虫的寄生囊，叫做包虫病
They're parasitic cysts from a bug called echinococcosis.
触摸死狐狸，它们跳上你
Touch a dead fox, they jump aboard
它们可以盘踞几十年
they can hunker down for decades.
成长、产卵，购物，上演戏剧
Growing, spawning, shopping. Putting on plays.
我做了寄生虫测试
I've been tested for parasites.
好吧，是癌症，你满意了?
Okay, it's cancer. You happy?
胞囊隔离寄生虫
The cysts isolate the parasites.
不让它们在大便检测中被查出来
Keep them from showing up in stool samples.
甚至是验血……
Even a blood test, cardiac--
好了，你不需要我帮忙干这个
All right, you don't need me for this.
但你的肝脏有同样问题
But you've got the same things in your liver.
我是硬化
I have cirrhosis.
肝脏胞囊症状相同，只一点不同,发烧
Liver cysts have identical symptoms. With one addition, fever.
肝脏胞囊我们可以测试
And liver cysts we can test for.
你的诊断可以验证凯的
Your diagnosis could confirm Kalvin's.
所以选项A－－我们抽血
So, option A--we draw some blood--
不，你们别碰我
no, no, look, you're not touching me.
看，这是我要你来的原因
See, this is why I need you here.
我要你告诉你儿子
I want you to tell your son
你不肯为挽救他的性命,做个简单的验血
that you won't take a simple painless blood test to save his life.
你从未对发生在你妈妈,身上的事表达过半点抱歉
You never expressed a shred of regret for what happened to your mother.
哦，爸爸
Jeez, dad.
如果你带套就没事了
If you'd have worn a damn rubber, you'd have been fine.
你或许能救她的命
You could have saved her life.
你也不会躺在这里
You wouldn't be lying here.
对，对，对，我明白了
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, I get it.
你对他的自杀行为很愤怒
You're really mad at him for killing himself
那毁灭了一切你爱的
and for destroying everything you love.
我没时间看这个
I don't have time for this.
你要道歉吗?
Are you gonna apologize?
我用我的方式过活
I'm living my life the way I want.
你要给我血吗?
Are you gonna give me some blood?
你看，如果他不在乎，那我也不
Look, if he doesn't give a damn, then neither do I.
好吧，B方案
Okay, option B.
为什么你太太自杀？,她恨你吗？
Why did your wife kill herself? Did she hate you?
她有糖尿病
She was a diabetic.
你知道，你根本不了解苏珊
You know, you don't know a thing about my Susan.
要么就是苏珊想死,要么就是又胖又蠢
Either Susan wanted to die, or she was both fat and stupid.
用闪光棒代替枪
Used a twinkie instead of a gun.
大胃口的女孩
And girls with big appetites
她们对什么都没够
well, they just can't get enough of anything.
- 闭嘴,- 也许咬过所有州里的海军陆战队员
- Shut up.,- Probably nibbled on every devil dog in the county.
- 闭嘴,- 天啊，我说的不够明白
- Shut up!,- Jeez, I'm not making myself clear.
我不是说美味的零食
I don't mean the delicious snack.
你个狗娘养的
You son of a bitch!
好啊，来吧
Yeah? Come on!
谢谢你，我就可以干这个了
Thank you. That means I can do this.
我们这里需要做EPI
We're gonna need some epi in here, stat!
你疯了吗?
Are you out of your mind?
你说过你不在意的
You said you didn't care.
注意到你无法呼吸了吗?
Notice how you can't breathe?
要么是因为我的手杖
Now either that's the cane
要么就是我刚打破了,一个我们聊到的肝脏胞囊
or I just ruptured one of those,liver cysts we were chatting about.
而你将进入过敏性休克
And you've gone into anaphylactic shock.
跟你儿子经历过的一样
Exactly the same when your son did
当他绊倒在我朋友的车上
when he accidentally tripped against my friend's car.
我太兴奋我找到原因了
I'm just so excited to find out which.
我去安排手术
I'll go schedule the surgery.
夹子
Clamp.
保持压力
Pressure's holding.
两个成功的手术，挽救了两个生命
Two successful surgeries, two lives saved.
我超额了
I'm over my quota.
我下周可以休息了吗?
Can I have next week off?
攻击了两个家庭成员
Two family members assaulted.
那是自卫
It was self-defense.
你引诱了他
You baited him.
你对，我自找
You're right, I was asking for it.
低胸外套，写着“干我”
The low-cut blouse, the "do-me" pumps.
你把他的内脏里灌满寄生虫,他可以诉你的
You flooded his gut with a parasite, he could sue.
去见史黛西
Go see Stacy.
好
Okay.
就这样吗？好？
That's it? "Okay"?
不骂人，不诉苦，不撕碎上衣？
No name-calling, no squawking, no rending of garments?
我喜欢这件T衫
I like this t-shirt.
你跟我扯谎
You lied to me.
如果是关于我妈的……
If this is about my mom--
是关于你孤独、悲惨的人生
this is about your lonely, miserable life.
我不悲惨
I'm not miserable.
而且只要周围有同性恋吧,我就不孤独
And as long as there's a gay bar around, I'm never lonely.
除了你爸，你连一个访客都没有
You haven't had a single visitor except for your dad.
毒品棒极了,HIV解放了你
Drugs are great. HIV freed you.
你爸爸恨你，你那么高兴吗？
Your dad hates you. You're so happy.
一切都是谎言
Everything's a lie.
你因母亲的死而责怪自己
You blame yourself for your mom's death.
你不是在寻欢作乐,你是在毁灭自己
You're not trying to have fun, you're trying to self-destruct.
你要杀了自己吗？,好吧，但是别再招募新兵了
You wanna kill yourself? Fine. But stop recruiting.
听说你又打了一个病人
Heard you hit another patient.
对，是啊，干嘛不呢？
Yeah, sure. Why not?
他先打我的
He hit me first.
卡迪没说，让我看看
Cuddy didn't mention that. Let me see.
我才是医生
I'm the doctor.
我的关系是纯粹合法的,好像没事
My concern is purely legal. Looks okay.
疼吗?
Does it hurt?
一点点
A little.
你需要点冰
You need some ice.
马克不可能不知道
There's no way that Mark doesn't know.
关于吸烟
About the smoking.
他该说点什么
He would have said something.
要不就是他已经数月没靠近你了
Then he hasn't been near you in months.
我们没事
We're fine.
不可能轻松
Can't be easy.
别乱动
Stop squirming.
你干嘛撒谎?
Why would you lie about this?
我没有
I'm not lying.
我不在乎你是否跟他睡觉
I don't care if you're sleeping with him or not
但你没有，所以……
but you're not, so--
我有
I am.
说谎
You're lying.
你知道如果我有性生活,你能闻出味来?
You know when I have sex, you can smell that on me too?
唯一知道发生在我和马克,身上事情的人
The only people that know about,what's going on with me and Mark
是我和马克
are me and Mark.
我就是知道你
I just know you.
而我也知道你
And I know you.
你自信、傲慢
You're confident, arrogant
但如果没有可确定的,你从不确定
but you are never certain unless there's a reason to be certain.
知道的另有其人
One other person knew.
我告诉你我在看哈医生
I told you I was seeing Dr. Harper.
你可以轻易进她办公室
You can easily get into her office.
你看了我的病例
You read my file.
盘子、关怀、那些……
The dishes, the concern, the, oh
人类的举止
acting like a human being.
你……
You have--
这段时间，你在操纵我
this whole time, you've been manipulating me.
你知道我也有垂钓时刻……
You knew that I had an angle the moment I--
往刷子上倒洗洁精
poured soap onto a scrub brush.
你可以把我扔出去
You could've thrown me out.
或者忽视我，或找另一个杀虫的
Or ignored me, or found another exterminator.
但你却没告诉马克我常顺道来
But you didn't even tell Mark that I kept coming by.
你任其发生因为你想跟我在一起
You let this happen because you wanna be with me.
我不再想了
I don't anymore.
滚吧
Get out.
对不起
I'm sorry.